transportdirect.info 2014-05-19

# Terms & Conditions | Transport Direct

## Privacy policy

### 1.  General

1.1  Transport Direct is a division of the Department for Transport whose main contact address for the purpose of this Privacy Policy is Portal Service Team, Transport Direct, Department for Transport, Zone 3/14, Great Minster House, 76 Marsham Street, LONDON, SWIP 4DR. (" **Transport Direct** ").   In the course of your use of the Transport Direct website located at www.TransportDirect.info (the " **Website** ") we will only collect your email address.   This Privacy Policy applies to the processing by Transport Direct of your email address.  By accessing and using the Website you are agreeing or have agreed to be bound by the Website Terms and this Privacy policy and you consent to Transport Direct holding, processing and transferring your email address as set out herein.   Transport Direct may at any time modify, recover, alter or update this Privacy Policy

### 2.  Transport Direct Use of Your Email Address 

2.1  Transport Direct will use your e-mail address to profile the Website to better suit your needs and to contact you when necessary. 

2.2  Other than is required by law or as set out in this Privacy Policy, Transport Direct will not disclose, rent or sell your email address to any third party without your permission.

2.3  Transport Direct will hold your email address on its systems for as long as you remain a registered user of the Website.  Transport Direct will remove it when requested by you. 

### 3\.  Cookies 

3.1  You should be aware that information in data may be automatically collected through the use of "cookies".  Cookies are small text files a website can use to recognise you and allow Transport Direct to observe behaviour and compile accurate data in order to improve the website experience for you. 

3.2  Most internet browsers enable you to delete cookies or receive a warning that cookies are being installed and if you do not want information collected through these cookies there is a simple procedure by which most browsers allow you to block or deny the cookies.  Please refer to your browser instructions or help pages to learn more about these functions. _However, for you to make best use of the site’s full functionality we recommend you do not block or deny cookies._  

3.3  Transport Direct will install a cookie named "TDP" containing the following details:

  * Session ID
  * Site theme id and domain
  * Last visited date and time
  * Last page visited

The cookie will be used to detect new or repeat visitors of the site. To opt out of this process, please follow your browser instructions or help pages to block or deny the cookies.

3.4  Transport Direct uses pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage online advertising. These GIF files are provided by DoubleClick and enable DoubleClick to recognize a unique cookie on your web browser, which in turn helps us to learn which of our advertisements bring most users to our website. The cookie was placed by us, or by another advertiser who works with DoubleClick. With both cookies and Spotlight technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not reveal your name, address, telephone number, or email address. For more information about DoubleClick, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to [www.google.com/doubleclick ](http://www.google.com/doubleclick/).

3.5  Transport Direct also uses page tag based web analytics. These services are provided by Intellitracker and Google Analytics, and help us to learn more about the usage of Transport Direct. The information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not reveal your name, address, telephone number, or email address. For more information about Intellitracker, go to [www.cognesia.com ](http://www.cognesia.com/index.php/) or Google Analytics go to [www.google.co.uk/analytics ](http://www.google.co.uk/analytics).
